if you're tight on space but you're
looking for a great way to get a low
impact cardio workout in at home you
might want to consider getting the
NordicTrack
se7i there's automatic adjustments that
are going to take place during the
middle of your workout there's an
endless amount of classes available from
iFit on the 10 inch touchscreen monitor
and it can be folded in half and be
stored vertically I've been using this
elliptical a lot lately and I'm excited
to break it down for y'all
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbin garage gym with another
review ready for you all today this time
around I've got the Nordic Track space
saver se7i elliptical in the gym for
review now in this video I'm going to
tell you everything you need to know
about this elliptical from the price the
features some pros and cons you may
experience while working out with it and
of course who should or maybe should not
purchase one of these before I do that
though if you don't already know we've
reviewed a lot of ellipticals on
barbin.com so if you want to browse our
best list well all you need to do is
search barbin best ellipticals that
article is going to pull right up for
you and you can find out for yourself
which ones that we like the best
[Music]
foreign
like about the se7i well to kick this
off I think we have to focus on the iFit
workouts as I mentioned there's an
endless amount right there for you to
choose from on that 10 inch touchscreen
monitor this is a really great tool in
my opinion because you know I think we
all know that cardio can be a little bit
boring sometimes and I don't think being
bored is something you're gonna have to
worry about because there's so many
different options for you to choose from
but just hang tight I'll dig into more
detail on that in just a second you also
have 22 levels of resistance with this
elliptical and during those trainer-led
workouts that's going to be
automatically adjusted depending on
which workout you're doing you also have
manual adjustments as well though so
that way you can adjust the difficulty
whenever you've seen fit you have a
built-in fan with four different speeds
to help cool you off and you have a
water bottle holder that way you can
stay hydrated when you're working out
which is obviously really nice there's
Bluetooth capabilities for your
headphones there's also a headphone jack
if you like going down the old school
route with some wired headphones it's
also Bluetooth capabilities for a heart
rate monitor which is definitely going
to come in handy in terms of keeping
track of your burned calories and
obviously your heart rate variability
there's also popular music loaded onto
the monitor as well and this is really
nice in my opinion so there's like 10
different radio stations for you to
choose from and this is just really cool
because a lot of these really high-tech
workout products nowadays tend to have
you know just some random Almost Boring
instrumental music loaded on there
that's not the case here you know you
have current up-to-date music but you
also have the classics on there as well
which is really cool since this
elliptical way is a pretty hefty 215
pounds thankfully there is a handle and
a set of wheels it's going to make it
pretty easy for you to move it around
your personal space but the se7i also
folds and it can be stored vertically
that way you're able to make the most of
your available space hence the name
space saver
[Music]
thank you
all right now let's take a second and
just talk about a few potential cons you
might experience with the se7i first of
all just because it can fold in half and
it can be stored vertically to make the
most of your space that definitely
doesn't mean that it's small okay so as
it's sitting here unfolded like it is
right now it's 67 inches tall and it's
about 80 inches long which is just over
six and a half feet so when you do in
fact store it vertically you know it's
going to be six and a half feet tall I
don't think that's going to be much of a
problem but I think when you're using it
when you're working out I think you need
to have at least seven feet of space
from your wall or else you know you run
into the risk of the movable feet and
arms kind of you know hitting your wall
and definitely don't want that this
elliptical also has an 18 inch stride
length now if you're somebody like
myself you're under six feet tall I
don't think you'll have much of a
problem with that whatsoever but if you
are over six feet tall you might have
some difficulty in terms of really
stretching out and getting that normal
stride length that you're used to before
I will wheel in the rear right here is
also an 18 pound flywheel I haven't
noticed anything wrong with that I feel
like it still provides plenty of
resistance for your workouts some people
might want a 20 pound flywheel because
obviously it can provide more resistance
I mentioned the water bottle holder and
how it comes in handy you know as you're
working out you start to sweat a little
bit get thirsty yeah it's nice it's
there but it's relatively small in my
opinion most reusable water bottles are
not going to fit in that holder so
definitely keep that in mind there's
also not any built-in heart rate sensors
either so definitely keep that in mind
if you're wanting to accurately track
your amount of calories you're burning
as you're working out you're definitely
going to have to get yourself a heart
rate monitor or if you have one just
pair it up with the Bluetooth that way
you can get an accurate reading let's
talk about the money as well so the base
price of this elliptical is listed right
around thirteen hundred dollars and
considering all the luxury features it
has I think it's a pretty solid deal but
still 1300 bucks that's not necessarily
cheap so you know if you don't want to
spend that much money on an elliptical
let's say you're not use it that often I
suggest saving you know hundreds of
dollars and finding yourself a much more
basic model out there on top of that
you're also going to have to pay for an
iFit membership just to gain access to
the available classes now first time
buyers are going to get a free month
after that you're either going to have
to pay about 40 bucks a month or sign up
for one of the three different yearly
subscription plans I'll dig into that in
just a second but just remember you know
that's going to add on to an already
expensive product and other than that
you know you definitely need to make
sure you have a strong Wi-Fi connection
I'm in the garage I'm not right next to
my router so it affects me more than
it's probably going to affect a lot of
you but you know there's so many
workouts loaded onto that monitor that
sometimes it just takes a good amount of
time just for everything to load and
buffer
[Music]
okay so as promised I'm going to expand
on the price now for the se7i so once
again the base price of the actual
elliptical is right around 1300 bucks
now your overall price is going to be
directly determined by whether or not
you want any additional warranty or
maintenance plan which route you decide
to go with your iFit membership and
whether or not you want white glove
assembly now if you go for the most
expensive options available you're going
to spending over 2600 bucks on this
product and that's definitely expensive
so fortunately you can in fact Finance
it and regardless of you know which
route you decide to go for all those
different variables NordicTrack does a
really good job of breaking everything
down and it gives you a couple different
options in terms of monthly payments
whether that be over a year or 39 months
so just be sure to check all that out
and just ultimately find out which one
suits you the best now 1300 bucks
definitely isn't cheap and if you don't
care about all the bells and whistles
all the luxury features that are here
and you just want a simple elliptical to
get a quick cardio workout in probably
going to be better off saving you know
hundreds of dollars by going for a more
basic elliptical but remember this is a
luxury product and considering 1300
bucks it's cheaper than some other
competitors that offer some of the same
features I think it's a pretty solid
deal
all right so now let's talk about some
of the available classes with iFit and
that iFit companion app I don't want to
spend too much time on this because a
you know I don't want to bore you to
death but B I could spend this whole
video Simply talking about all the
classes through iFit I'm not kidding
when I said there is an endless amount
there's over 16 000 for you to choose
from and that is actually growing as I'm
sitting here talking into this camera
right this second so you know whether
that be you know hopping on this
elliptical and doing some cardio workout
whether you want to stretch do some yoga
maybe listen to a TED Talk bust out some
dumbbells do a strength training class
you name it iFit has it and the cool
thing is you can do all this from that
companion app so you know those classes
that I mentioned that don't involve this
elliptical you know you can stream all
of that from your phone from your tablet
whatever you're deciding to use and you
can do that on the road as well so you
know say you're going on a quick trip
you know hop in the car you know throw
some dumbbells in there wherever you're
staying Airbnb Hotel you can get a quick
workout in which is really nice Plus on
top of tracking all of your stats on
this monitor that's all going to be on
the app as well it's going to track your
past workouts the challenges you're
trying to complete challenges you have
completed you name it it's right there
okay so clearly this is a pretty
high-tech piece of equipment so I kind
of just want to detail some of that
technology for you so once again you do
in fact have a 10 inch touchscreen
monitor it's where you're going to have
access to all the iFit classes right
there at your fingertips which is pretty
cool you'll notice on the top of that
monitor though there is you know a
camera unfortunately that doesn't have
any purpose right now but you know in
this day and age what we have with
virtual training becoming such a popular
thing I wouldn't be surprised if that's
rolled out in the not too distant future
you have automatic adjustments that are
going to take place with the 22 levels
of resistance and that motor is honestly
relatively quiet which is definitely a
nice thing for those who like to work
out late at night or early in the
morning you also have two two inch
speakers located directly underneath the
Monitor and they provide a pretty solid
amount of sound as you're listening to
your trainer or the music both whatever
you want to do it sounds pretty solid to
me I also love how NordicTrack teamed up
with Google Maps for all their cardio
equipment it's a really cool tool in my
opinion because you can pick any city in
the world make your own route and you're
going to be able to like kind of visit
that City in a certain sense and it's
going to give you that Google camera
Street camera it's on top of a car
whenever they you know ride around you
see them riding around town it's really
cool in my opinion it's not a perfectly
seamless transition of all the time but
it's still pretty cool nonetheless it's
also Bluetooth capabilities this is
going to be really nice for those who
like having an accurate measurement of
the number of calories they're burning
while working out it's also going to be
nice for those who want to stream their
workout classes with their Bluetooth
headphones but you know if you don't
have any maybe you don't like using
Bluetooth whatever you can also go the
old school route and just plug in a good
old-fashioned pair of wired headphones
as well the monitor operates on Android
9 OS technology so it's nice and up to
date you won't have too much of a
problem in terms of lagging with the
interface you know loading menus this
and that as long as you have a pretty
solid Wi-Fi connection and on top of
that you have a built-in fan I can't
forget to mention that it's going to
help cool you off as you're working out
with four different speeds
okay so let's talk about the build and
highlight some of those features one
more time for you guys the framework
right here with the se7i is in fact made
of steel it feels really durable really
sturdy when I'm working out with it I
don't feel as if it's you know unstable
and that it's going to topple over as
I'm working out which is obviously a
really nice thing it's about five and a
half feet tall just over six feet long
and it's just under three feet wide so
definitely keep that in mind whenever
you're looking to find the right spot
for it to go in your home it weighs 215
pounds so thankfully you do have that
handle and a set of wheels it's going to
make it really easy for you to move it
around your personal space it also has a
325 pound weight limit which is a really
high number when it comes to cardio
equipment longevity also really
shouldn't be an issue for you guys I
don't think because there's a 10 year
warranty on the framework and that's
just a really nice safety blanket now
when it comes to those features I've
already talked about all of these I just
want to highlight them one more time you
do have that 10 inch touchscreen monitor
and it's gonna allow you to gain access
to the available classes it does tilt a
little bit as well that way you can kind
of you know accommodate to your comfort
level with your neck and while you're
looking at it I guess this monitor is
also going to attract a lot of metrics
such as your time spent working out
distance traveled in your speed it's
also going to give you an estimate on
the amount of calories you're burning
while working out but remember you know
there's no built-in sensors so if you do
in fact want a super accurate reading
all you need to do is hook up your own
heart rate monitor there's automatic
adjustments that are going to take place
during the middle of your workout what
those 22 levels of resistance but you
can always manually adjust everything as
well if you choose to do so on top of
that you have that built-in fan to help
cool you off and a water bottle holder
you know to stash a basic water bottle
remember not every single reusable water
bottle is going to fit in that cup
holder on top of that though the cherry
on top that I think makes this
elliptical stand out from the rest is
the ability to fold in half and be
stored vertically
[Music]
all right so I want to walk you guys
around this elliptical and kind of
demonstrate how everything works before
I do all that I want to take you to the
back of it first as you can see you have
your wheels right here it's really nice
in terms of portability but beside each
wheel you have a little foot right here
that's how it's going to be able to be
stored vertically and that's really nice
it's also going to be right here is a
little bit of a foot plate I guess you
could call it with this flywheel right
here you know it's going to be resting
on that so that's how you know
everything really happens it's your 18
pound flywheel I haven't noticed
anything you know negatively in terms of
the resistance but some people like
targeting a 20 pound flywheel because it
can offer a little bit more resistance
overall this is a pretty quiet flywheel
which is you know obviously a really
good thing now let's move a little
further up
these are your oversized foot pedals
they're about 13 inches or so I don't
have my rule I don't have my ruler or
tape measure with me right now but I
think it's about 13 inches off the top
of my head now cool thing is these can
be adjusted there's three different
heights they can be positioned at so you
can technically make this a little bit
more of a quad driven workout if you
want to and that's really easy to do you
just pull out this plastic Tab and raise
up or push it down whichever way you're
wanting it to go that's really easy to
do I'll explain how to fold it and kind
of show you in a second but just while
we're sitting right here this knob right
here you're going to twist on it until
it can be pulled out and there's a tab
right here you'll lift up on and that's
how you're able to fold it all right now
it's your water bottle holder as you can
see it's pretty small not every single
reusable water bottle is going to fit in
there so definitely keep that in mind
you might be better off with a good old
classic
non-reusable water bottle all right now
let's get into the good stuff this is
your touch screen monitor it's 10 inches
it can be rotated a little bit as you
can see or Tilted should I say that way
you know you can just kind of for your
comfort level you can find the right fit
for you
we're on the home page right here right
when you pull it up you know it's going
to show you your past seven days you
know your workout stats distance total
time estimated calories burned and
that's really cool you can click on this
right here it's going to show you daily
obviously weekly monthly and yearly now
we can scroll through right here and
there's a bunch of workouts that are
available right off the bat
you know there's
I'm in the middle of this 20-part series
I haven't gotten too far I guess you
could say but you know whenever you
complete one and you're doing that it's
gonna pop up right here that way you can
jump right into the next one and kind of
you know keep tabs of everything click
on calendar down here it's going to pull
up all of your most recent workouts show
you how long you're doing them estimated
calories burn how far you went
everything like that click on create
this is really cool to me all right so
we're in Mexico now watch this I'm gonna
exit out of here go back to create
now it has this in Cambodia do it again
just to show you this is going to pop up
a new city every single time which is
just mind-blowing to me we're back in
Mexico but you get the gist it's going
to do the same thing over and over now
you go to browse this is the full
Library you're able to find every single
workout that you know directly
corresponds with this elliptical and
that's really cool
um you can find you know search by
trainer there's different challenges
right here these are being added all the
time which is just really cool to me so
that way you know you're not going to
reach a point to where you've done every
single available challenge if you do let
me know I'm actually gonna be really
interested in finding that out if
somebody's able to do that there's also
different categories you know less than
20 minutes Beach City desert and you
kind of name it right here you can kind
of scroll a little bit trending series
as well short workouts you know if
you're new to iFit guys there's a lot
going on right here there's also an
on-air tab it's going to show you right
down here it's going to take a second to
load
but it's going to show you all the
upcoming live oh my finger would work
right there there we go it's going to
show you all the upcoming live classes
that are going to be available and
that's just really sweet in my opinion
it's going to take a while to load so
just know that that's there just
remember that now go back to the home
page on this left side pull down that
menu you edit your account you can edit
other accounts so you can have up to
four additional accounts on your
membership so five total which is really
cool you can basically split everything
five different ways you know which is a
really nice thing now you have your
manual adjustments right here for your
resistance as you can see there's 22
different levels right here and you know
that's really nice you know if you don't
want to sit here and have the machine do
everything for you you can just kind of
click and this is all going to be
directly corresponded to whatever you
know level you're wanting to go to your
fan is located right here and you can
tilt this which I think is actually
pretty nice comes in handy at certain
times you know that way you can you know
adjust it to you know hit you in the
face hit your
torso you know whatever fill in the
blank it's there and you have your
adjustments right here for the volume
and the fan now let's say you don't want
to pay for iFit well you don't really
have to and I think you should because I
think it's definitely how this is meant
to be used but you do have a manual
start option right here and I'm just
going to hop on this now and as you see
it's going to kick in it's going to give
you a warm-up and it's going to track
all your metrics up here at the top and
that's going to be during all of your
trainer lead workouts as well so it's
going to show your speed estimated
calories burned obviously it's going to
be accurate if you do in fact have a
heart rate monitor that you want to hook
up it's also going to show your time
elapse resistance there's a lot of
different metrics that are right here so
it's going to give you a warm-up we're
just going to end it for right now I'm
good to go it's going to give you a
little quarter mile track and then
you're basically good to go so this is
an 18 inch stride length once again you
know I don't have any problems with it I
Feel Pretty Natural when I'm moving get
these movable arms make you feel like
you're actually running
but you know like I said if you're over
six feet tall
that stride length may not be ideal for
you because you're not going to really
be able to open up your hips fully
now
other than that everything is smooth
sailing you know I'm going to go ahead
and adjust my resistance I'm at the
hardest one right now
and you can't really even hear anything
this is a really quiet machine so that
way you know if you're working out late
at night early in the morning you have
roommates family members you live in an
apartment complex
you're not going to wake up everybody
and you can't forget about that
Bluetooth
pair up your headphones
and it's a quad experience now
let's go ahead and one more thing I
forgot to mention before I show you guys
how to fold this is you do have your
auxiliary in right here if you don't
want to use Bluetooth headphones and you
also have your two two inch speakers
right here which provide a pretty solid
sound
all right now let's do this all right so
what you do is UN twist this knob right
here
all right good to go and once again you
have this tab back here you're going to
lift up on it
sometimes it makes a loud noise at these
two plastic pieces but and other than
that you just kind of be gentle with it
you know it's not a toy
and that's it that's all you got to do
with it and I have mine plugged in right
now so I'm not going to move it around
right this second but you have your
handle up here so you just lift right
here
and then you can store it vertically
once again once you don't have it
plugged in which is really nice you know
as you can see like it really cuts down
on that footprint especially when it is
stored vertically and we all like that
hence the name space saver
[Music]
okay so now it's time to answer two of
the hardest questions I'm gonna be asked
about this elliptical the first one
being who should buy it well if you're
tight on space or maybe you just want a
piece of cardio equipment that's going
to allow you to make the most of your
available space I think this is really
one of the better options that are out
there you know once again it can be
folded in half and be stored vertically
so that way you can tuck it in the
corner of your room it's just kind of
out of the way of everything and you can
do any other type of workouts that you
may want to do we got to talk about iFit
too you know once again there's tens of
thousands of classes available at your
fingertips on this touch screen monitor
but they're also going to be available
on that companion app as well so you
know whether you want to do some yoga
some stretching some meditation some
strength training listen to some TED
Talks the list goes on and on and on
that membership is going to wind up
being worth it for a lot of y'all
watching and then lastly you know since
this is such a high-tech luxury product
it has a price tag of right around
thirteen hundred dollars if you're
looking for the best bang for your buck
piece of cardio equipment I think you
found your match
foreign
question here is who shouldn't purchase
this elliptical well let's talk about
the money yes I just got done saying
it's one of the best bang for your buck
purchases in terms of cardio equipment I
still think that's true but not
everybody wants to spend thirteen
hundred dollars on one piece of
equipment so if you don't want to do
that well you don't have to nobody's
going to twist your arm and make you do
it so if you want to save some money you
can definitely find a more basic cheaper
option out there we also got to talk
about space yes this is labeled as a
space saver it's designed to make the
most of your available space but it
still could dominate too much of your
room and two more things here if you're
over six feet tall you might have some
difficulty in terms of really opening up
your stride because the stride length
here is only 18 inches and some people
may not be too crazy about the 18 pound
flywheel because it simply may not
provide enough resistance
well that's all I have for you guys
today on the NordicTrack space saver
se7i elliptical I think this is a great
product overall but especially for those
who are tight on space and want to make
the most of what they have available
can't forget about those automatic
adjustments to your resistance or the
ability for it to be folded and stored
vertically you tie in all those awesome
features for Price types right around
thirteen hundred dollars I think you've
got a really great deal thanks for
hanging out with me all I hope this
video was really helpful and that I was
able to break down everything you need
to know about this product as always
stay posted for my next video but for
now if you want to read more on this
elliptical all you got to do is search
bar Bend NordicTrack space saver se7i
elliptical review our detailed article
is going to pull right up for you and
you can go over everything that we
talked about here today I'll catch y'all
next time
foreign
[Music]